Maybe just one question.
Before today, maybe just
Maybe just
>> [cheering]
>> My my apologies for just jumping into it
and grabbing a mic, but I I really have
something that's bothering me on the
topic that you introduced, man of God.
Always clear these microphones here.
>> All right.
>> Thank you for the opportunity to ask
questions so that we learn more.
And
>> [music]
>> my concern, or would I say my challenge,
it's becoming more like a challenge for
me.
You spoke about the divine [music]
nature
and us being one with Jesus.
Being united with him and being one
spirit with him.
But then
my
concern really emanates from
what I believe many are experiencing or
many believers are experiencing, but I
would want to focus it on myself.
Which is the aspect of
being one with Christ, but yet having
certain things that I look at and I say
this is not consistent with being one
nature with God or we one nature one
nature with Christ.
Things like
elements that follow bloodlines.
Elements that follow bloodlines.
>> [applause]
>> Firstly
maybe giving an example of myself and
where I come from.
You would find that it's
Jesus says, "I'm the resurrection and
the life." Which means I'm one with the
resurrection. I'm one with the life.
Which means I am resurrection. I am
life.
But there are certain things which when
I look at in my family, they are
uh
bloodline
issues.
Take for example, my grandfather died of
cancer.
My father also died of cancer.
And
many of his siblings, even my
grandmother died of cancer. So, you look
at that information
considering that
blood also carries some information, and
I'm still carrying the same body. Being
born again and being one with Christ
with this body uh how do I activate the
the divine nature in me to surpass and
go beyond
family lines. Also, to add to that,
you'd look at aspects of
uh
marriage life.
In my generation, marriage is really an
issue.
Many who who marry
they marry more than one.
At the same time or in different times,
but it's more than one. That's the
order.
And
for
my generation my siblings you'd find
that in a family of nine people only one
person is
>> [music]
>> married.
The rest are not married. And you'd
wonder, if I am I'm not doubting that
I'm one nature with Christ, but these
things that I see around me now makes me
wonder
how do I how do I activate the nature of
Christ
to to change this pattern
to change this this line.
>> [applause]
>> And
lastly, just to add to things that when
I look at are not consistent with
my
oneness with Christ.
Still in the generation, you you look at
poverty.
>> What?
>> Poverty.
>> Okay.
You see
at times it's difficult to explain,
but you just have to see that this is
it.
This is poverty. You you you don't need
to be taught.
But yet still
I'm able to look at that. When I'm
saying poverty, I'm saying
there are thresholds and certain limits
which you know
in in in family line,
no one has gone beyond this line. No one
can go past this line.
But
if I am one with Christ,
how how do I become
the Christ in the family to save myself
and my generations?
>> [applause]
>> So, this is the concern, men of God, and
I know there's something that you've
you've dropped in in all of us, and we
want it to really come out.
>> [applause]
>> I don't know. Is it
Is it maybe need for us to be laid hands
again? I don't know because you've laid
hands on us several times.
But at times you wonder, how many times
have I been prayed for? How many times
is the hand of God been laid on me? But
why does it seem like I still have
many of these things following
following me, but yet I'm one with
Christ?
>> [applause]
[cheering]
[applause]
>> Yeah, you seem to be having a lot of
support.
>> Amen.
I would have wanted to look for the
different question,
but then with this kind of support
>> [cheering]
>> All right.
You were very very good, very very
clear
and precise in terms of
the way that you've you've asked that
question.
Um
The answer to such a question requires
quite a lot
of attention.
People have to pay a lot of attention.
A lot.
>> [sighs]
>> I think from your question, you kept on
emphasizing
on the fact that you
you have a a generation that you're
coming from.
>> Yes.
>> And most of these things that you see
happening to you
uh is a result from your question uh is
a result
of where
you are coming from.
So,
usually we would read from 2 Peter,
right? That's our
2 Peter what?
Uh
okay.
>> 2 Peter 1:3
>> Uh-huh.
>> According as his divine power
>> Yeah.
>> have given unto us all things that
pertain unto life and godliness.
>> reading on 4, right?
>> Uh-huh.
>> Ver-
Verse 4.
>> Mhm.
>> Whereby are given unto us
>> Exceeding
>> exceeding great and precious promises
>> Mhm.
>> that by these ye might be partakers of
the divine nature.
>> That by these we might be
partakers of the divine natures.
It's good that the the the question is
coming from what we've just been
teaching.
Being partakers of the divine nature.
Now, looking into your question, I would
want you to look
look at um
Romans chapter 8.
Um
verse 17.
Verse 17 or verse 18. Let's go verse 16.
Romans
Let me see.
Yeah.
Chapter 8, verse number 16 and verse 17.
Verse 16, 17, Romans 8. This is directed
to you now.
Not just you, the rest of the people
here who are having that same question,
listen to this one.
>> The spirit itself beareth witness with
our spirit.
>> The spirit itself bears witness with our
spirit
>> that we are the children of God.
>> It's confirmed at a spiritual level. The
spirit itself bears witness with our
spirits that
we are
the children. Whose children?
>> Of God.
>> Whose children?
>> God.
>> God is what?
>> Children.
>> God is who?
>> We have to start from there.
Cuz
in an attempt to answer
that question
fully, I have to also appreciate
where the question is emanating from.
You have asked
a generational question.
You are talking
of a father
and your father's father
and your father's father's father.
And right here, in terms of being born
Again, I'll get to that at some point.
We are being introduced to something
completely different.
It's easy finding it in scripture. I
know it's difficult finding it in your
own life.
What we're about to talk about.
The spirit itself bears witness with our
spirits that we
not of your ancestors.
There must be that
unity of purpose. There must be an
agreement between two spirits.
That from today going forward, you'll
manifest
as God's baby.
God's child.
We are the children
of God.
If ever we are going to believe in that,
that we are children of God, then we
must have things
that once happened to God happening to
us.
If you believe in inheritance,
>> [applause]
>> if you believe that you have inherited
poverty, you have inherited cancer from
your father,
here comes an introduction now to a new
father.
I want you to still maintain the same
belief.
If the poverty you have is as a result
of having a connection to a father that
was poor,
please keep
that understanding.
Maintain that belief
until we introduce a new father.
We are the children of God and because
of that, let's go That was verse 16,
right? Look at verse 17. Verse 17.
>> Yeah.
>> And if children
>> If children
>> then heirs.
>> If we are children, then heirs.
Inheritance.
You're complaining here as a child and
you're complaining over the inheritance
of cancer,
of poverty.
And it's given to you by virtue of being
a child. If we are children, then heirs.
What entitles you to inheritance is
being a child.
That's why a child is here raising a
question.
So, you're complaining of an inheritance
that you got from your father.
You are given a right to inherit from
your father because you are what? A
child.
Now, scripture here is saying
if children, then
>> then heirs.
>> Then heirs.
>> Heirs of God
>> and joint heirs
>> with Christ.
Now,
if your father were to give you
anything,
it can be money,
it can be a house,
it can be a disease,
cancer. It can be
poverty.
Now, this passage of scripture now talks
about if we are children, then we are
heirs. Yes.
Which means we
have the right to inherit from a father
in verse number 16.
We have a right to also inherit
from a father if it is confirmed that we
are indeed by the spirit children of
God, then we are entitled to an
inheritance
from our father.
Right?
But in this passage of scripture, if you
look at it carefully, verse number 17,
and if children, then heirs, heirs
of God,
and joint heirs with Christ.
Now, being an heir
of God,
this is not in reference to you
belonging to God.
Being an heir of God, it means you are
an inheritor
not from God, but of God.
It's [applause]
it's God that you inherit.
Not money from him,
not a car from him,
not a house from him.
It's him you inherit.
Heirs
of God.
It's not heirs of God in terms of the
fact that you belong to God. We are
talking of being an heir who inherits.
Your inheritance is who?
Not God
anything.
God is in a better position. We can't
compare him to any of your biological
forefathers.
We have worked so hard to leave
something for you.
God has done everything to make himself
available so that you can inherit him.
The person of God, the nature, the very
nature of God.
He has to become your inheritance.
Where you don't walk around showing
people things that you have received
from God. You walk around showing people
God.
heirs
>> [applause]
>> heirs
heirs
of God
Exactly what God said to Abraham, I will
be
come your exceeding great
reward.
>> Genesis 15:1 I am thy shield and thy
exceeding great reward.
>> I'm your protector, I'm your shield and
your what?
>> exceeding great reward
>> Because why God is giving himself as a
reward because he exceeds
everything.
He notices if I give you anything,
you'll still come back for more.
So, the highest level of wealth
is himself.
And he says, "Abraham, at your level of
belief
in me
I no longer have to be giving you
things. Now I have to offer myself
so that you become an heir
of God, not from God, of God."
Oh, you're here.
I thought you had gone home.
All right.
So when God becomes
what you inherit, this is what happens.
When God becomes
your possession,
not only are you owned by God,
you have him.
There is a level of ownership
where you own God, not in terms of
controlling him.
But God is the most valuable
not asset, not thing, personality
not only that you possess, but that you
are.
To inherit
God.
You walk into the office
just about to be shown what you're about
to receive, and he says there is nothing
here except myself.
Work so hard from now to make sure that
you possess me,
own me,
inherit me.
Personalize me.
Think about this for a moment. Why is it
that you're saying your father's father
had cancer, your father had cancer, your
mother had cancer?
And obviously that becomes a concern to
you.
Now what I want you to understand is
that even if you're not going to have
cancer in any part of your body, you
already have cancer in your mind.
You see?
Yeah, you can't be thinking of cancer
and not having it.
There's nothing that you can think of in
your head and you don't have it in your
head. Nothing.
There is nothing. If it's a car, you
have it in your head.
If it's money, you have it in you. If
it's marriage, you have it in you. If
it's cancer, you already you have
you have
a brain a cancer cell in your brain.
So, don't wait for it to be to to have a
diagnosis and then you're told that you
have it in a certain location. Already
you have cancer in your
It has already occupied a certain part
of your body, which is your brain, if
you can keep thinking of that.
You have it.
This is why keeping thinking of things
of God, you have God already in your
mind. Now, scripture talks about
>> [applause]
>> whatsoever be good, whatsoever be just,
think upon these things.
When your mind is locked on what is
positive,
whatsoever things are true, whatsoever
things are honest, whatsoever things are
just, whatsoever things are pure,
whatsoever things are lovely, whatsoever
things are of good report, if there be
any virtue and if there be any praise,
think on these things.
He has given you a list of things that
you need to start focusing on.
And you're looking at the list, there
isn't your forefather there, there isn't
any cancer there, there isn't any
poverty, any suffering.
So, he's trying to set your mind
to regulate your thinking
so that eventually by thinking on that,
you become that.
Why is it that you have a forefather who
had it, you have a father who had it,
you had a mother who had it, and you are
worried about that?
Now, myself, having a father who never
had that, having a father's father who
never had that, having a mother who
never had I'm not worried about that,
and yet your forefather and my
forefather all came from Adam.
So, what's happening?
Why do you have it in your lineage and I
don't have it in my lineage and we we
all emanated from the same source?
It means there is something that Adam
never had.
That your forefather invented.
Your forefather might have taken a case
to a different level
beyond what he had received from Adam.
So, he cannot even blame Adam for
handing it over to him. Adam can
actually point it my Sekuru Makandiwa
and say, "How come in this lineage,
if you are blaming me for giving it to
Chigumira's lineage,
how is it there is other lineages that
are not having that manifestation, if
I'm to blame for that?"
It means there must be something that
your forefather did
that you must investigate and never do.
Never do.
>> [applause]
>> The day, Chigumira, you stop thinking
like your father, you are excommunicated
from your lineage.
>> [applause]
>> What connects you from to your father
is the way you think.
>> [snorts]
>> Let's talk about investigation a little
bit.
Because this question is investigative.
I hope you were listening when he was
asking.
He was talking you were speaking like a
detective.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
This gentleman is coming from history.
He's wondering why is it that what's
happening to me happened to my father.
What happened to my father is exactly
what is happening to me.
Yet you're coming here talking about
divine nature, divine nature, divine
nature, one with Christ.
I'm looking at myself I'm realizing that
I'm one with my forefather.
>> [snorts]
>> What I would want all of us here
to
start investigating
is how
we got born again.
How
did you get born again?
That is going to answer
all of these other questions.
If you can forget about the rest of the
questions and your question becomes one,
which is how did I get saved?
Cuz I believe all these must be laid
upon the foundation of salvation.
If that foundation is faulty,
what can the righteous
do?
If the foundations be destroyed,
what can the righteous
do?
When scripture says, "If the foundations
are destroyed, what can the righteous
do?" It's not saying the righteous can't
do anything. It's simply a question. The
righteous ought to answer that question.
If the foundations be destroyed, what
can the righteous do?
It doesn't mean that you can't do
anything.
It's simply a question. The righteous
are supposed to then find ways of
answering that question. What can you
do?
Now realizing that you're the righteous
of God and yet your foundation is
faulty, what can you do?
There must be something that we can do
as the righteous
to correct the foundation.
If the way that you got born again
was faulty,
the the rest of your manifestations
as a child of God
will be faulty.
Salvation being the basis,
being the foundation, if it's it's if
it's flawed, don't expect any any of
your manifestations
to be perfect.
Whatever you do, you manifest as this,
you heal, you cast out demons, you
prophesy, you are prophesying from a
faulty foundation. If you are not
properly and thoroughly and fully born
again,
you can't manifest in full in any other
way.
So, any inconsistencies in of your
manifestations can be traced back to
your foundation.
You can't heal well if you are not saved
well.
You can't prophesy well if you are not
saved well.
You can't discern well if you are not
All of these manifestations of the
spirit have to come as a result of the
condition of your salvation, the
condition, the quality of your salvation
will manifest in your manifestations.
The quality of your salvation.
What you are talking about
was once my study.
Man of God, I did a serious thesis.
I did a comprehensive survey. I digged
extensively into my physical genealogy
wanting to know what are the things that
are forbidden
in our generation.
And I came up with a list of things and
I said, "For me to know that I've been
fully delivered from Makandiwa's
generation, I have to do this." I have
things that I do not because I like
building a house. No.
It's because it was it's forbidden.
I do those things just to test whether
I'm still a part of that generation or
I've escaped corruption.
You have to you look for certain places
where you go and you stay
in certain locations
simply because that location is not
consistent
with the programming of your blood.
No one ever lived there, so you go there
just so that you test
and you see how long you're going to
stay in that location without any
trouble.
It's a test just to see whether you're
still in that lineage or you've been
delivered.
Now,
>> [snorts]
>> and when people see us
manifesting that we have a problem, they
don't know what we've been trying to run
away from.
So, I'm giving it to you in stages.
There is a moment when I used to believe
that. That was also once my belief.
>> [snorts]
>> That what I'm seeing happening to me is
happening to me because it also happened
to my father.
Sit down, please.
If you really want me to work on this
question, let's agree that this is going
to be the only question today.
All right. Okay.
All right.
>> [laughter]
>> I don't want to be talking while I'm
wondering what is going to be the next
question.
Let's exhaust this one.
Investigation is very important. I'll
come back to the aspect of
investigation.
You said that you have
issues of the blood.
A woman came to Jesus who had issues
of blood. The issues of the blood are in
two ways. Not issues as in stories of
the blood, but also issues in terms of
issuing
of the blood. She was issuing
blood.
Blood was issuing, flowing out of her
body. That was the issue of blood.
So, wherever this woman would go,
she would be issue. She would manifest
the blood.
Nothing of God, nothing of divine
nature, nothing of the spirit. It was
blood coming out of her body. Whatever
she does, she starts a business, she
will bleed into that business.
She would bleed.
She marries a man, she would bleed
into that relationship.
And she wanted that to stop.
And she looked for a man
that you have found.
She looked [applause] for him.
All she wanted was not to be in Christ.
She all All she wanted was to touch.
And you are in him.
She looked for the man that you
currently possess, who is
your inheritance.
And she said, "If I can only Why only?"
She's saying, "There is a generation to
come
which will have a greater privilege
of being in him, but in my generation,
if only I can touch
from external.
Such a man with such an anointing, with
such grace
is capable of stopping blood from
issuing.
Yes, by touching.
Not by having him. Not by being born
again.
Cuz he she was disadvantaged by her
generation.
She was a generation before the cross.
Having problems before the cross.
Issuing blood before the cross.
But she said, "Since I'm distant
generation, all I can do is to stretch
my hand
from where I am
into the New Testament. If I can touch
only the hem of his garment,
I shall be made well."
And what she did
was to
look for him.
Which is a part
that you're not going to do.
She looked for him.
Oh, Jesus.
She looked Sit down, please. She looked
for him.
Because she had the question
the issue
of blood.
Issue of blood.
Who can stop this?
She had been to different places,
different physicians, different witch
doctors.
And she got worsened.
Meaning they did something to her.
It means she didn't go there for
nothing.
It means these people had an ability to
make it worse.
>> I built an app that rewires [music] my
brain every day using a neuro
science-based technique. There is a
method that
>> an ability to make it worse.
Which means they also bled
into her situation.
These were people that had issues with
their own blood.
Wanting to redeem and to help others
that had issues with their blood.